Oliver Denton

DATA SCIENTIST | TECHNICAL WRITER

07964022921

9 36 Pickard Crescent,

@ ojdenton1@sheffield.ac.uk

Sheffield, S13 8EY

https://oliverdenton.github.io/portfolio/



in /in/oliver-denton1

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Studying Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science has made me a methodical and analytical student who is not afraid to ask questions or learn new skills and languages quickly. My interests lie in backend development and machine learning. I look forward to working with new technologies and frameworks to help me establish a clearer vision for my career and gain experience in the field. Keen writer with an eye for detail.

EXPERIENCE

A.I. Research Intern

June 2021 - Present

Defence Science and Technology Laboratory (U.K. Ministry of Defence)

Designing, developing and testing deep learning models using Python and PyTorch. Evaluating model architectures with a focus on generative adversarial networks. Role also involves presenting and demonstrating new code or ideas.

Technical Writer (Freelance)

March 2021 – Present

Data Driven Investor

In write articles in my free time for a popular online publication. I mostly write about artificial intelligence and digital finance. Role involves careful research, planning as well as listening and taking in feedback.

Remote Camp Tutor

May 2021 - Present

Fire Tech

Helped lead several courses teaching Java, Python and other introductory courses to small groups of children aged 8 – 17. Involves lesson planning, teaching and giving useful feedback.

Team Member

May 2017 - June 2021

Gregas

Started working at the age of sixteen. Most of my time was spent on the shop floor serving customers and fulfilling other responsibilities. Learned about cash handling, following instructions, taking the initiative and clear communication.

Industrial Placement

Summer 2018

Metalysis Materials Discovery Lab

Spent time in both research and development and analytics departments. Key responsibilities included running and maintaining electrolysis experiments and taking and measuring samples. Attended several seminars and helped develop a neodymium-iron-boron alloy for magnets. Learned about integrating with new teams and using unfamiliar procedures and software.

EDUCATION

MComp Artificial Intelligence and **Computer Science** 2019 - Present

University of Sheffield

• Second year overall grade: 83.0%

- First year overall grade: 75.7%
- Scrum master and technical writer in second and first year software engineering group projects. Created a 'bookmark management system' using Ruby, SQLite

A-Levels

2017 - 2019

Aston Academy

- Computer Science A
- Physics A
- Mathematics B
- Extended **Project** Qualification (Quantum Computing) - A*

GCSEs

2012 - 2017

Aston Academy

• 9A*s, 2As, 1B (including Mathematics - A*, Computer Science - A*)

SKILLS

Java Python **Technical Writing** Machine Learning PyTorch CSS Haskell **JavaScript**

REFERENCES

- Maria-Cruz Villa-Uriol, Personal Tutor and Lecturer m.villa-uriol@sheffield.ac.uk
- Gavin Jackson, Shop Manager, Greggs Earl St. - gaviinj@yahoo.com
- Ian Mellor, Managing Director, Metalysis ian.mellor@metalysis.com
- Lee Nicholson, Head of Sixth Form and Physics Teacher lee.nicholson@astonacademy.org